Guide to the Renee C. Fox and Samuel W. Bloom medical student project papers, 1950-1953.
Fox, Renee C. and Samuel W. Bloom medical student project papers, 1950-1953.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Renee C. Fox and Samuel W. Bloom medical student project papers, 1950-1953.
4388
Renee C. Fox.
3.2 cubic ft.
Field notes, interviews, and diaries.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The papers consist of three kinds of materials: field notes of situations, e.g. meetings, classes, informal gatherings, etc. observed by the field workers; informal interviews with faculty members and students in the Cornell University Medical College and the University of Pennsylvania Medical School; and diaries kept by a number of students selected to represent different stages of training and different kinds of interests.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The papers consist of three kinds of materials: field notes of situations, e.g. meetings, classes, informal gatherings, etc. observed by the field workers; informal interviews with faculty members and students in the Cornell University Medical College and the University of Pennsylvania Medical School; and diaries kept by a number of students selected to represent different stages of training and different kinds of interests.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Fox, Renee C.; Bloom, Samuel W.; Cornell University. Medical College.; University of Pennsylvania. School of Medicine.
Subjects:
Medical students.; Sociologists.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Field Notes, Volume I, July 20-Nov. 5, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
- Field Notes, Volume II, Nov. 9, 1953-Mar. 24, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
- Field Notes, Volume III, Mar. 24-June 9, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
- Field Notes, Volume IIIb, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
- Field Notes, Volume IIIc, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 12-15)
- Miscellaneous reading notes, Volume IIId, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Wilmot Ball, Fourth Year Student, Volume IVa, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 17-20)
- Harold Brew, Fourth Year Student, Volume V, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
- Harry Cassell, Fourth Year Student, Volume VI, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 23-26)
- Lowell McLellan, Third Year Student, Volume VII, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 27-29)
- Dana Brooks, Second Year Student, Volume VIII, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 30-33)
- Ronald Rosenback and Walter Menninger, First Year Students, Volume IX, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 34-36)
- Dana Brook Diaries, Volume X, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
- John Patrick Donahue, First Year Student, Volume XI, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 4-6)
- John L. Brown, Jr., Fourth Year Student, Volume XII, Diary, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
- W. Walter Menninger, Jr., Second Year Student, Volume XIII, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 9-11)
- W. Walter Menninger, Second Year, Volume XIV, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 12-14)
- W. Walter Menninger, Volume XV, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 15-18)
- W. Walter Menninger, Third-Fourth Year Student, Volume XVI, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 19-21)
- W. Walter Menninger, Third-Fourth Year Student, Volume XVII, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 22-24)
- W. Walter Menninger, Internship, Volume XVIII (Box 2, Folder 25-27)
- W. Walter Menninger, Third Year Student, Interview (original draft) (Box 2, Folder 28)
- 1. Penn Field Notes, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 29-32)
- 2. Penn Field Notes, Jan.-May 1954 (Box 2, Folder 33-35)
- 3. Penn Field Notes, Sept. 1954-May 1955 (Box 2, Folder 36-39)
- 4. Appendix to 3. Field Notes, Sept.-May 1955 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
- 5. Penn Field Notes, Sept. 1955-Mar. 1956 (Box 3, Folder 4-6)
- 6. Penn Stanley Taub, Fourth Year Student, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- 6. Penn Robert Aiken, Third Year Student, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- 6. Penn William Bunney, Second Year Student, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
- 7. Penn Peter Jenney, Second Year Student, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- 7. Penn Alison Bradley, First Year Student; John Senior, Third Year Student; Mat Aborensen, First Year Student, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- 7. Penn Donald Burns, Second Year Student, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- 8. Donald Burns, Second Year Student, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
- 9. Penn Alan Balsam, First Year Student, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 16-19)
- 10. Penn William Bunney, Third Year Student, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
- 10. Saul Weinberg, Third Year Student, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
- Complete Internship Seminar Notes, Soc. 319 and 320, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
- Field Journal, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 26-29)
- MGH - Dr. Lindemann's Group Counseling, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Cornell IIIc and IIId Field Notes, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Field Notes: Selvin, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
- Profile on Student H (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Profile on Student F (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Note cards (5x8) - Field Notes (?), 1953-1957 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- A Study of Medical Education, Opinions and Experience of Medical Students, University of Pennsylvania, 1953: Questionnaires (Box 4, Folder 1)
- A Study of Medical Education, Opinions and Experience of Medical Students, University of Pennsylvania, 1954: Questionnaires (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Journal of W. B., Second Year Students, 1953-1954 (originals) (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Student interviews: W. Reid, 10-28-53-1/13/[54]; Stanley Taub, 10/26/53-1/12/54; A. B., 9/14/53-5/12/54 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Notes: Field Notes, Reading Notes; 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
- Renée C. Fox Field Notes, II, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 7-10)
- Student Journal: D. B., Second Year Student, 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Student Journal: D. B., Third Year Student, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Anatomy Lab Workbook, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Journal of Saul Weinberg, 3rd Year Student, Volume I - December 1954-May 1955 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Field Notes, S. W. Bloom, Vol. III, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Mary Goss' Report on the Comprehensive Care and Teaching Program of Cornell Medical College, July 20-Oct. 20, 1953; Field Notes/Fox (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Diary of Dana C. Brooks, Second Year Student; 10/7/1953-6/7/1954; Renée C. Fox, interviewer (Box 4, Folder 17)
- A Sociological Calendar of Medical School, Part I: First Year, Renée C. Fox, June 1955: Working Paper No. 3 (2 copies) (Box 4, Folder 18)
- A Sociological Calendar of Medical School, Part II: Second Year, First Trimester; Renée C. Fox, February 26 1956: Working Paper No. 3, also Second Year, Second Trimester; R. C. Fox, June 1956, Working Paper No. 8 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- "psychiatric social worker teaches medical students," Nation Association of Social Workers, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Patient Relationships: Old and New Programs; Mary Bright Rowan and Mary Jean Huntington; January 1957; Working Paper No. 1 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- A Sociological Calendar of the First Year of Medical School, Renée C. Fox, June 1958 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- The Effects of the Cornell Comprehensive Care and Teaching Program on the Attitudes and Values of Fourth-Year Medical Students, Patricia L. Kendall and James A. Jones with assistance of Candace Rogers, November 1960 (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
- The Relationship Between Medical Educators and Medical Practitionaers: Sources of Strain and Occasions for Cooperation, Patricia L. Kendall, September 1962 (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
- Notes from University Seminars on the Professions, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
- "Summary and Analysis of Replies Received in answer to the Questionnaires on Emotional Needs sent out by Preparatory Commission No. I on Community Needs," Conference on Psychiatric Education, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY, June 21-27, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Appendix: Movie Study, Ca. 1951 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Marcia Steinberg study on HIP (Health Insturance Plan of Greater New York), 1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Cornell Journals Wilmot Ball 4th Year Student I (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Cornell Journals Wilmot Ball 4th Year Student II (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Field Journal Vol. 1 1955-56 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Student Journal AB First Year Student 1954-1955 I (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Student Journal AB First Year Student 1954-1955 II (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Diary of Walter Menninger Cornell 2nd Year Student I (1953 - 1954)(1954 - 1955) Renee Fox (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Diary of Walter Menninger Cornell 2nd Year Student II (1953 - 1954)(1954 - 1955) Renee Fox (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Field Journal April 22, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Renee Fox-Notes Diary of Henry Erle Nov. 18, 1953 Second Year Class (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Fraternities Medical (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Journal of Alan Basalm 1955 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- S. W. Bloom Field Journal 1955 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Biographical Questionnaires and Bloom Field Reports (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Field Notes - Chance (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Journal of Alan Balsam II 1955 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Bloom - "Lecture - U. of P. Orientation - Sept. 9, 1954" (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Analyses - SWB (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Questionnaire Analyses: Preporatory Materials for the 1956 Institute on Evaluation of the Student - The Appraisal of Applicants to Medical Schools (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Field Journal Volume I S.W. Bloom 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Field Journal Volume II S.W. Bloom 1954 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- FHHS (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Field Notes (Box 5, Folder 27)